Finding Aid for the Katherine Philips Edson Papers LSC.0235
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence (1909-1920)
  - (July-December 1914), 92 pieces
    - Walter Mathewson., Alexander McCabe, labor vote in Hiram Johnson's victory, prohibition, minimum wage amendment on ballot, election campaign, San Francisco city government. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Walter Mathewson., Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Walter Mathewson., John P. McLaughlin's desire to place a friend on Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Walter Mathewson., Robert Telfer, Alexander McCabe, John P. McLaughlin, L.W. Butler and Labor Commission. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., Katherine Philips Edson's testimony before Federal Industrial Relations Commission, Gertrude Beeks. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Walter Mathewson., Hiram Johnson, John P. McLaughlin, E.H. Hancock, Industrial Welfare Commission and civil service, Mathewson's friends in San Jose, Alexander McCabe, vote on minimum wage amendment, Harry Scheel. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger-- Gertrude Beeks., Katherine Philips Edson, U.S. Chamber of Commerce convention. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Gertrude Beeks-- Ben F. Schlesinger., Vocational training legislation in California, Dean Herman Schneider of University of Cincinnati, Katherine Philips Edson, Frank P. Walsh. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Walter Mathewson., Francis Heney, James D. Phelan, Olaf A. Tveitmoe, Woodrow Wilson, Mike Kelly, Joe Kelly, graft in California, San Jose's new administration, business manager type of city government. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Chester Rowell., Hiram Johnson's ways, consolidation of labor departments, John P. McLaughlin, Meyer Lissner, Progressive conference in East. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Clinton R. Woodruff., Katherine Philips Edson's reelection to council of National Municipal League. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Walter Mathewson., John P. McLaughlin, Hiram Johnson.; News clipping on American Federation of Labor (AFL) stand against labor legislation, Samuel Gompers. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Walter Mathewson., Comment on Samuel Gompers and American Federation of Labor (AFL) stand. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Walter Mathewson., Hiram Johnson, Albert Bonnheim, Labor Commissioner's office. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Clara Schlingheyde., Katherine Philips Edson's cancelled trip East, Hiram Johnson campaign. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Hiram Johnson., Girl's Training School Board vacancies. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Chester Rowell., University of California site for citrus experiment station. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Chester Rowell., Dr. Adelaide Brown for appointment to State Health Board, Edwin T. Earl, Dr. Sherwin Gibbons, Dr. John Randolph Haynes. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Hiram Johnson., Dr. Sherwin Gibbons, Edwin T. Earl, Edward Dickson, Dr. James McBride, Girl's Training School Board. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Walter Mathewson., Harris Weinstock, A.B.C. Dohrmann, California industry and higher wages, Stockton's open shop agreement, Paul Scharrenberg, Olaf A. Tveitmoe, P.H. McCarthy. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - (telegram) Hiram Johnson., Board of Health position. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Walter Mathewson., Assemblymen Dan R. Hayes and Theodore Wright, industrial commission bill, Senator Herbert C. Jones. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - (January-June 1915), 64 pieces
    - Mabel Deering., San Francisco Chronicle, woman suffrage. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Carrie C. Catt., Proposed federal woman suffrage amendment.; Suggested form for a resolution of the California Legislature on woman suffrage.; Clippings against suffrage from San Francisco Chronicle and pro-suffrage from Woman's Journal. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Helen Bary., Harry Scheel, Industrial Welfare Commission, using women to study local industries. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Helen Bary., Resigning from Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Carrie C. Catt., Woman suffrage in East, asking for resolution from California Legislature. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Walter Mathewson., Industrial Welfare Commission, enforcement of rulings, apprenticeship, competition from cheap labor, minimum wage, Hiram Johnson, Albert Bonnheim, Immigration Commission, Paul Scharrenberg, John P. McLaughlin, Labor Council. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Walter Mathewson., Article in Organized Labor by Grant Hamilton on minimum wage and Industrial Welfare Commission, Olaf A. Tveitmoe, Samuel Gompers. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Meyer Lissner., Dr. Sherwin Gibbons, State Prison Board's Duffy, Railroad Commission's Harvey D. Loveland, Hiram Johnson, coming election, Sebastian, Wallace and Senator John D. Works' seat, Earl papers, Francis Heney, Willis Booth, George Patton. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Walter Mathewson., Minimum wage, Industrial Welfare Commission, unemployment plan, Hiram Johnson, Albert Bonnheim, Helen Bary, Judge W.A. Beasley's decision on picketing.; Clipping on Judge Beasley's decision. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - (telegram) Ben F. Schlesinger., Katherine Philips Edson's trip East, Fr. Prosser. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - (telegram) Walter Mathewson. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Hiram Johnson--Mayor Charles D., Unemployment in California, army of unemployed marching on Sacramento and Washington, D.C. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Heywood., International Workers of the World. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Mrs. N. Whitehouse., Woman suffrage in East, James Rolph, Jr. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Walter Mathewson., Building Trades Council convention. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., Assembly bill against inter-insuring. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., Introducing Harry Clark. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Chester Rowell., Medical bill, Senator Irwin. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Charlotte A. Whitney., Congressional Union for Woman Suffrage, proposed federal woman suffrage amendment. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Walter Mathewson., Industrial Welfare Commission work, apprentice bill, Paul Scharrenberg, P.H. McCarthy. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Walter Mathewson., Lumber industry, Professor Carlton H. Parker. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - J...S...R... -- Hiram Johnson., Asking leniency in the case of Mrs. M.E. Davis. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Charlotte A. Whitney., Congressional Union for Woman Suffrage. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Mary O. White., Asking information on Industrial Welfare Commission jurisdiction. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Maude Wetmore., Anne Morgan, Ben F. Schlesinger. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Hiram Johnson., Anti-vivisection bill, Dr. John Randolph Haynes. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Anne Morgan., Arthur Williams, woman suffrage, Progressive Party, Amos Pinchot. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - (telegram) Anne Morgan., Arthur Williams. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - L.A. Haskins (Managing Editor for Los Angeles Tribune)., Katherine Philips Edson's letter to the editor of the Los Angeles Tribune. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Harriet Odgers., Request for monetary aid from Hiram Johnson for the Lowes. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Dr. James McBride., Thanks for support against anti-vivisection. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bertha von der Nienburg., Canning industry. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Norman R. Martin, County Superintendent of Charities., Request for aid for the Lowes. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Lillian J. Haley, Department of Charities., The Lowes' case. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Walter Mathewson., State Civil Service Commission and Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - (July-August 1915), 45 pieces
    - Walter Mathewson--Helen Bary., Katherine Philips Edson's health and work habits. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Walter Mathewson(?)--Al McCabe(?)., Katherine Philips Edson's health and finances. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Lolita Van Rensselaer. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Meyer Lissner. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Walter Mathewson., P.H. McCarthy, andrew J. Gallagher, Industrial Welfare Commission and canners, A.B.C. Dohrmann. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Hiram Johnson., Los Angeles Labor Bureau. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Chester Rowell., Rowell's writing and its influence. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., Edson family. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - William D. Stephens., John I. Nolan. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Walter Mathewson., Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Walter Mathewson., Harry Scheel, Industrial Welfare Commission, Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - (September-December 1915), 59 pieces
    - Harriet Vittum., Woodrow Wilson, Charles Evans Hughes, election campaign. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Ethel McC. Adamson., Clipping on woman suffrage, asking statement on suffrage from Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Harry A. Scheel., Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Nellie S. Clark--Hiram Johnson., Asking information on 8-hour law in California. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Harriet Odgers. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Ethel McC. Adamson., Katherine Philips Edson's refutation of anti-suffrage statements. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Editor, New York Tribune., Asking statement from Katherine Philips Edson on New Jersey suffrage defeat. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Grace C. Simons., Hiram Johnson and incident with speaking engagement at Friday Morning Club, jury bill. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Meyer Lissner., Friday Morning Club incident, Grace C. Simons. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Labor unions, International Workers of the World, P.H. McCarthy, Ford and Suhr matter. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - P.H. McCarthy--Walter Mathewson., International Workers of the World, Ford and Suhr circulars. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Ford and Suhr circulars, P.H. McCarthy. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - John Frances Neylan., Bowen pamphlet, consolidation of several commissions with Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Meyer Lissner., Lissner's appointment to Industrial Accident Commission.; Clipping from San Francisco Examiner, by Frona E.W. Colburn: against suffrage, Mrs. Arthur Murray Dodge, Jane Addams, Hiram Johnson, Annie Laurie. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Hiram Johnson., Enclosed clipping. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - W.N. Binest--Walter Mathewson. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., Legislation on interest rates, State Senator William E. Brown. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Harry Scheel, A.B.C. Dohrmann, P.H. McCarthy. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Helen Bary. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Hiram Johnson's election fight, Harrison Gray Otis, De Young, Judge W.A. Beasley, Judge Richards, Bob Telfer, Jay O. Hayes and John D. Fredericks. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Helen Bary., Charles Farwell Edson. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Violations of 8-hour day, Labor Bureau, J.P. Denehy, John McLaughlin(?). (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Harry Scheel. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson--Helen Bary. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Election campaign, Bob Telfer and Harrison Gray Otis, Jay O. Hayes, Chester Rowell, Judge W.A. Beasley, Frank Benson. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Election campaign, Bob Telfer. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., John P. McLaughlin, Harry Scheel, Alexander McCabe, Industrial Welfare Commission, Judge Frank J. Murasky, Albert Bonnheim. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Industrial Welfare Commission, Hiram Johnson, Alexander McCabe, John P. McLaughlin, Harry Scheel, Frank Benson. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Jurisdiction of state laws, Judge Frank J. Murasky, Clarence Coolage, Industrial Welfare Commission work, canning industry. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Helen Bary. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Canning industry, coming election. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walter Mathewson., Harry Scheel, A.B.C. Dohrmann. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - (January-April 1916), 54 pieces
    - Walter Mathewson., Helen Bary, Bertha von der Nienburg, A.B.C. Dohrmann, Industrial Welfare Commission adjustments. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Walter Mathewson., Helen Bary, A.B.C. Dohrmann. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Helen Bary-- Walter Mathewson., Resignation changed to leave of absence, working conditions in Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - (telegram) Helen Bary. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Helen Bary. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Walter Mathewson., Katherine Philips Edson's canning industry report, Harry Scheel, A.B.C. Dohrmann. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Cyril Charles Sanders., Judge Willis I. Morrison, 3 R Mine Company. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Freeman H. Bloodgood., Wage board work. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - John A. Ryan., California Industrial Welfare Commission and similar commissions in other states, Louis Brandeis, U.S. Industrial Relations Committee, George P. West, East Youngstown strike, minimum wage and constitutionality, Joseph R. Lamar. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Florence Kelley., Louis Brandeis. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Willis I. Morrison., John Eshleman's funeral. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Walter Lippman., Theodore Roosevelt. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - John P. McLaughlin., Katherine Philips Edson's request for leave of absence news clipping on anti-suffrage and anti-Johnson people. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Chester Rowell., California lieutenant-governorship, Judge Clarke, Meyer Lissner. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Hiram Johnson., Appointment of women to government positions, Immigration and Housing Commission, Mary Gibson, Helen K. Williams, Prison Board, Philaletha Michelson, Clara Shortridge Foltz, Olive Olive C. Cole, United Republicans, de Young, Harrison Gray Otis, John D. Spreckels, Jay O. Hayes, Joseph R. Knowland. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Florence Kelley., Massachusetts government, Governor McCall, Minimum Wage Commission, New York Industrial Commission, divergence in wages of clerks and factory workers, health insurance, commission government in U.S. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Helen Bary., Industrial Welfare Commission reports, Marie Obenauer, Bertha von der Nienburg, woman suffrage plank for national Republican platform. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - (telegram) Robert N. Bulla, Paul J. McCormick, Harriet Strong, Miguel Estudillo, Egbert J. Gates, Joel S. Crail., United Republican delegates (candidates for positions as delegates to National Republican Convention) stating support for woman suffrage plank, countering charge of being anti-suffrage by San Francisco Chronicle. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Lawrence J. Flaherty--Executive Committee, Women's United Republican League., Supporting woman suffrage. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Miguel Estudillo. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Robert N. Bulla. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - John A. Britton. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Raymond Benjamin. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - F.E. Ellis. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - T.S. Montgomery. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - James Madison. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Egbert J. Gates. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Harriet W.R. Strong. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Women's United Republican League, Executive Committee., Open letter on primary election of Republican delegates to National Convention, urging United Republican (progressive) ticket; Regular Republicans, Olive C. Cole. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - (May-December 1916), 55 pieces
    - Walter Mathewson., Defeat of United Republican ticket of convention delegates, conditions in mines. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hiram Johnson., Effect of anti-suffrage statements on Olive C. Cole's defeat, Mrs. Strong, Miss Ogden. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hiram Johnson., Defeat of United Republicans. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Florence Kelley., Supreme Court and Oregon minimum wage case, Justice Joseph R. Lamar, Justice Charles Evans Hughes, Justice Louis Brandeis, Justice Day, Justice Baker, New York State Court of Appeals' reversal on women working at night, Massachusetts Minimum Wage Commission, wage boards' makeup, New York Industrial Commission, Lynch, Newton D. Baker. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Bertha von der Nienburg., Garment industry, recommendations for wage rulings. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Edward A. Dickson., Charles Evans Hughes and Republican nomination, Boies Penrose, Crane, Barnes, Frances A. Kellor, women's vote, Theodore Roosevelt, Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Meyer Lissner., Consolidation of commissions having to do with industrial welfare, Bradley. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Walter Lippmann., Republican nomination, Progressives, Theodore Roosevelt. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Meyer Bloomfield., Employment Managers' Association. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hiram Johnson., Hughes Alliances, Edward A. Dickson, Frances Kellor, Chester Rowell, Charles Evans Hughes, William H. Crocker. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Chester Rowell., Charles Evans Hughes and Woodrow Wilson and woman suffrage, Raymond Robins, National Woman's Party, Hariett Vittum, Republican suffrage plank. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Meyer Lissner., Urging concentration on Hiram Johnson and California campaign for present, Ellie Mosgrove, list of candidates for California Republican ticket, William D. Stephens, Dr. John Randolph Haynes. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Mary Gibson (with note added by Hiram Johnson)., Campaign work. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - George McLeod., Election campaign. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hiram Johnson., Primary victory. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hiram Johnson., Luncheon for senatorial candidates, effect of anti-suffrage views on candidates at polls, Olive C. Cole, Patton. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hiram Johnson., Anti-suffrage candidates, Regular Republicans, San Francisco Chronicle and Los Angeles Times.; Notes and names. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Mrs. M. Harbough (?)., Experience and qualifications for helping Hiram Johnson or running for office, Mrs. Moulton. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - ?, Campaign. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Florence Kelley. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Marie L. Obenauer., Industrial Welfare Commission reports. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Meyer Lissner., Epstein and Cable for position. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins., 8-hour day, Frances Noel's interview with Mrs. Robins. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Meyer Lissner., Harrison Gray Otis' attack on Johnson, Edwin T. Earl, Chester Rowell, A.H. Naftzger, William D. Stephens, Alexander McCabe, Joel Crail, San Francisco Bulletin and Francis Heney. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Lolita Van Rensselaer., Asking about California progressivism, Charles Evans Hughes' defeat in presidential race. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Chester Rowell., Position for Meyer Lissner (?). (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Marie L. Obenauer., Suggestions for Industrial Welfare Commission investigations, national election. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Florence Kelley., Robert La Follette, federal 8-hour bill. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hiram Johnson., Edward A. Dickson, Harrison Gray Otis' second attack on Hiram Johnson for allegedly undermining Charles E. Hughes in California election, Chester Rowell, Edwin T. Earl. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Frances A. Kellor., National election, Miss Kellor's article. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - (1917), 64 pieces
    - Ellie Mosgrove., Florence Kelley. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hiram Johnson., Successor to Albert Bonnheim on Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hiram Johnson., Cora Woodbridge wants Industrial Welfare Commission appointment. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Ellie Mosgrove., Progressives and Regular Republicans. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bertha von der Nienburg., Canning industry reports, U.S. Children's Bureau. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Republican State Central Committee., Requesting donation to clear campaign debt. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hiram Johnson., Industrial Welfare Commission appointment, Cora Woodbridge. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Meyer Lissner., Gray compensation case, Dr. Hunter. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Meyer Lissner., Gray case, Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Meyer Lissner., Gray case. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - William D. Stephens., State Council of Defense. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Dr. John R. Haynes., Child labor bill, interest rate bill, Edwin T. Earl, Brougher. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Martin Madsen., Appointment of Alexander Goldstein to Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - John C. Macfarland., Community property bill, State Senator Herbert C. Jones. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - John C. Macfarland., William D. Stephens, community property bill. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Carrie C. Catt., Congressional resolution on proposed federal suffrage amendment. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - William D. Stephens., Market commission bill. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hiram Johnson., William D. Stephens, Edward A. Dickson, A.H. Naftzger, Brundige. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Republican State Central Committee., Asking for contributions. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., Minimum wage. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Martin C. Madsen--Barbara Nachtrieb. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bertha von der Nienburg., National League for Woman's Service, war contracts. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hiram Johnson., Industrial Welfare Commission and minimum wage decision, John Francis Neylan. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Edward A. Dickson., Minimum wage decision, Harris Weinstock. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Ellie Mosgrove., Chester Rowell, Archer Bordwell, direct primary. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hiram Johnson., William D. Stephens, Edward A. Dickson, A.H. Naftzger, Woodrow Wilson. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins., Wartime contracts, etc., Raymond Robins, Kerensky. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Newton D. Baker--Mary Dreier., Committee on Women's Work in War Time, national minimum (wage?). (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Samuel Gompers., Appointing Katherine Philips Edson chairman of Women in Industry Committee of U.S. Council of National Defense. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Chester Rowell., News carriers and 6:00 law. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Edgar A. Luce., Possibility of Katherine Philips Edson's charging Los Angeles Times with libel. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - John Francis Neylan. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - John H. McBride. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Clinton R. Woodruff., Los Angeles Times' attack on Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hiram Johnson., Shipping Board appointment, Los Angeles Times attack, Edward A. Dickson, Edwin T. Earl, William D. Stephens, U.S. Senate. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Chester Rowell. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - (telegram) Harris Weinstock--Chester Rowell., Rowell's editorial on Los Angeles Times' attack on Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Martin C. Madsen., Recommending Richard J. Jose. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Martin C. Madsen--Walter Mathewson., U.S. Labor Commission investigation of California conditions. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Walter Mathewson--Martin C. Madsen., Industrial Welfare Commission report to Labor Commission. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Jessica B. Peixotto. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Meyer Lissner. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - John C. Macfarland., Industrial Welfare Commission report to U.S. Labor Commission. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Clinton R. Woodruff. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Dr. James H. McBride. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Grace C. Simons., Women in agriculture under the Council of Defense, Myrtle Shepherd Francis. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - (1918), 96 pieces
    - Jessica B. Peixotto., Illinois combining Women in Industry with Child Welfare. (Box 2, Folder 13)